It was an age of war.
Relying only on his own skill,
one man wandered the land.
A samurai.
This man
is not a wandering samurai of today.
Good morning.
-Morning.
-Sit down. Breakfast's almost ready.
No...
No breakfast today.
Huh? Why?
Are you on a diet?
No way!
I get a catered lunch.
Catered?
See you! Bye-bye!
It all started...
when I ran into an old friend.
An extra?
Like the extras in shows and movies?
After retiring, I had a lot of spare time.
I tried it, and it was a lot of fun.
How much does an extra get paid per day?
Well, it's not a lot.
About 3000 yen.
But getting a glimpse of myself
on the big screen behind
a star is a thrill.
And the catered lunches they serve
are delicious after a bit of work!
Really?
With lunch as my main goal,
today is my big screen debut.
What if a talent scout picks me up?
After retiring,
he lost his title as a corporate man
and the support of his company.
Takeshi Kasumi, 60 years old.
This story
is about a normal 60-year-old man,
who is helped by a masterless samurai,
eating freely without being held back.
A gourmet fantasy.
BENTO LUNCH ON SET
This is taking forever.
Calling all extras!
Yes?
Sorry, everyone.
-Okay.
-Sorry!
-Wait just a bit longer.
-This guy again.
Get back here!
Yes, sir!
-Excuse me.
-Yes?
Why hasn't the filming started?
We're waiting on sound.
-Sound?
-Yes.
You hear the construction over there?
We can't film with the noise.
-Oh, I see.
-I'm sorry.
-Osamura! Come here!
-Yes!
The road to lunch is looking
very long.
Is this your first time?
Yes.
I thought so.
It's pretty obvious.
Your costume stands out
more than you.
A bit condescending.
It's okay. Everyone starts that way.
My name is Suwa.
I'm Kasumi.
So, do you work as an extra?
Today is my 120th appearance.
That many?
Appearances? As an extra?
Well, if you have any questions,
just ask me.
Okay.
Is that...?
CATERING COMPANY
SANBYOSHI
-Please help if you're free.
-Okay!
Ugh, are they catering today?
They're popular in this industry.
I bet this is going to be
a mediocre movie.
What? You can tell from the lunch?
Of course.
You must know about
when Director Kurosawa
placed a prop inside of a chest
that was off-screen?
No, I don't.
A skilled worker pays attention
to things off-screen.
Lunch included.
If possible,
there will be a hot lunch to raise morale.
The preparation of a good meal,
or lack thereof,
has a large impact on the film.
Well...
What about today?
Subpar.
-Wait a moment.
-Understood.
Yes, then we'll make do with that.
For that we'll use an extra.
I'll look for an extra.
Do that later.
What is going on?
Sorry. It's impossible.
Listen, when Maiko looks back,
start to cry.
Attention, extras!
Sorry!
Please wait a bit longer.
-Sorry!
-Excuse me.
What are we waiting for this time?
Well, the actress and the director
are disagreeing about something.
-Director--
-I'm done!
Wait, wait!
Osamura! Osamura!
-Yes!
-What are you doing? Go get her!
-Yes, sir!
-We're losing light!
Yes, sir!
Asami! Asami! Asami!
Please, wait a minute.
Osamura, get over here!
Give her time.
-Mr. Suwa.
-Yes?
What's that?
Maybe pork soup.
Since they don't serve enough,
sometimes local volunteers
make us food.
Ugh, this sucks.
I didn't think it'd take this long.
Yeah. I'm tired.
I want to go home.
What kind of childish nonsense
are you saying?
What?
Waiting is part of working on films.
You shouldn't complain
over a few hours of wait time.
Have more pride in your job!
This isn't our job.
This guy is crazy.
Let's go.
Kids these days.
Right, Kasumi?
What?
I didn't know either...
that we would wait this long.
This is just the start.
Once, after waiting for 12 hours
for a period drama,
filming was pushed
to the next day.
What?
It never ends.
I may not get lunch
or dinner.
Come on, pull it together.
It's so hot out here.
What a waste.
I'm exhausted.
You idiot.
How is she doing?
Please, just wait a minute.
Unbelievable.
It's all that conceited actress' fault.
Princess!
We beg you!
That cannot be done!
We beg you to consider our request.
We are in dire need of her assistance.
-Please!
-The princess wishes to return home.
Move out!
Whoa.
What are you doing!?
Hey!
Clear the way.
Princess Whinesalot
is in this palanquin.
Don't disturb us.
You're disturbing my meal.
Insolent swine!
What are you doing?
Hey.
How long are you going to sulk?
Come and show them your face.
A flower's life is short.
To wilt in this dark space...
would be a waste.
Mr. Samurai! What is your name?
I am not worthy of a name.
Spectacular.
Please do something. There's no time.
Sorry. When she's in a bad mood,
she won't listen.
What? I don't care.
Really, I couldn't care less!
-We're off schedule.
-I understand.
Alright. Let me...
...persuade her like a samurai.
We're losing daylight, you know.
We're behind.
Give me some time.
-How much time do we have?
-Well...
You're that extra. What do you want?
Look, look!
My boyfriend replied!
"Let's take a trip after your film."
Yay! Wait a minute!
Director! Director!
I'll do the lines like you wanted!
Let's go now!
-You will?
-Yes!
-Ready?
-Yes, ready!
I guess she's a woman
before she's an actress.
Pardon me.
Well, I guess not.
If everything checks out,
we will begin shooting!
Then, the guy in the trainer...
Come this way a bit.
Then when I say "action,"
Mr. Suit Guy, start to walk that way.
Excuse me. Can I look at my phone
and adlib a bit?
No, don't do anything extra.
Understood.
So,
when Mr. Suit starts to walk,
Mr. Trainer head that way!
Also, please take care
not to look at the camera.
Okay, here we go!
Extras are ready!
Okay, here we go! Rolling!
Rolling!
-Rolling?
-Rolling!
Scene 28. Cut 3.
Ready!
Action!
Hey...
-actually I--
-Don't tell me.
What?
I don't want to know the truth of it.
Thank you! Okay!
Time for lunch.
How was your first appearance?
I got nervous
and didn't know right from left.
I'm sure. But you'll get hooked.
Hmm, I suppose so.
All I did was walk,
but it felt like an accomplishment.
It's like being in a school play,
but as an adult.
Here.
-Here, take this.
-Thank you.
Mr. Suwa.
What's the fancy lunch box?
That's probably an actor's leftover.
Leftover?
Some don't like to eat cold lunch,
or they're on a diet.
So, we have a chance of
getting their lunch?
It's really not that big of a deal.
Just a boxed lunch.
Is that a leftover?
Oh, I'll have it!
Thank you!
He made us wait all that time
and only he gets the nice lunch.
-Hey!
-That's not fair!
There's meat or fish.
Meat, please.
Should I choose meat?
Or should I choose fish?
Mr. Kasumi, there are people waiting.
Oh, pardon me.
Uh, well--
It doesn't matter, they're all the same.
Let's get some pork soup.
-Thank you.
-Yes, of course.
-It's hot, be careful.
Smells great.
Be careful, it's hot.
-Thank you.
-Nice work today.
Nice work today.
Mr. Kasumi, let's go.
Yes, okay.
That was a lot of pepper.
Thank you.
Here you go.
It's refreshing.
Hot pork soup after being on set
is the best.
We meet at last.
Mine's fish.
Mr. Suwa.
It's an ordinary boxed lunch.
Of course it is.
What were you expecting?
It'd been a while
since I've had a lunch box.
The pickled plum's color
is the red of Japan.
The flames of the sun.
A symbol of life.
The white rice that surrounds the plum.
Innocence and honesty.
A symbol of purity.
True, the food's cold.
But oddly, it doesn't taste that bad.
Well...
where should I start?
While I am tempted to have
the main course of grilled fish first...
...but I must start with the omelet.
Delicious!
A perfect supporting role.
Ah, it burns.
On to the main course?
No, not yet. Don't rush.
This seasoning
goes great with the rice.
I'm eating too much of the rice.
Time for the salad to play its part.
The time is ripe.
The yellowtail teriyaki.
Delicious! Just the right amount of fat.
Not too greasy at all.
Grilled fish and rice...
I'm glad I was born in Japan.
Mr. Kasumi.
Yes?
Is it that good?
Yes, it is.
It's just a plain lunch,
but eating it under the clear sky
makes it special.
Thank you!
There's some left.
What?
The parsley.
I never eat the parsley.
Who would eat parsley, right?
Like the extra who
never gets the main part.
No, not at all. I'm going to eat it.
I just forgot.
It's bitter.
I...
want to be an actor.
An action star like Jackie Chan.
An action star?
Being 45 years old, everyone says
that I'm being foolish.
Mr. Suwa,
where do you usually work?
I work part-time at a convenience store.
I quit my regular job
so I could attend auditions.
He's a bit reckless.
If I become famous one day,
please boast
that we had lunch together.
I will.
Attention!
We'll begin filming again in 10 minutes!
Ten minutes, everyone!
Get ready please!
Okay!
All right, let's get rolling!
All right!
Let's get ready!
Okay!
I'm on it!
Really?
So, it's hard work being an extra.
Very hard work.
Shizuko.
Huh?
Actually, I have a gift for you.
Really?
Like a celebrity's autograph?
-No, no.
-What?
Ta-da!
Catered lunch!
Dig in!
This is the lunch
you were looking forward to.
What's inside?
They let you bring this home?
Yes. Help yourself.
Oh, thank you.
Well...
It's good.
Um, it's...
not that good.
Oh, really?
Let me try.
You're right.
When I had it earlier,
it was delicious.
It's because you were hungry.
Fresh-cooked food is
always the best.
What!? No way!
What?
What is it?
Did we win the lottery?
No.
It's more surprising than that!
A 45-YEAR-OLD NEW COMER
CHOSEN FOR THE MAIN ROLE
Amazing. How'd he do it?
Subtitle translation by
Jeffrey Hales